Guide to the Leroy Olsen Papers 1948-1984
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Leroy Olsen Papers
1948-1984
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 803
Olsen, Leroy C.
1 linear foot of shelf space 2 boxes
Project reports, master's thesis and dissertation, and other scholarship by Leroy C. Olsen, professor of education at Washington State University.
Leroy Olsen (1921-1984) was a professor of education at Washington State University from 1955 to 1984. He was born and raised in North Dakota, and served in the United States Navy in the Pacific during World War II, surviving the attack on Pearl Harbor on December 7, 1941. After the war, he attended the University of North Dakota, earning undergraduate and graduate degrees (Bachelor of Philosophy in psychology, 1948; Master of Science in psychology, 1949; Doctor of Education in counseling and educational psychology, 1955).
This collection consists of documents related to Leroy Olsen's research in educational psychology. It includes his master's thesis and dissertation, reports of government-funded studies, and unpublished manuscripts.
This collection is arranged in a single series.
This collection is open and available for research use.
The Olsen family donated this collection to the Washington State University Libraries in 2013, via Ruth Funabiki (MS.2013.29).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington State University -- Faculty -- Archives
Picture interpretation tests; Students -- Psychology
Colleges and Universities
- A Comparative Study of Hull's Postulates and Previous Experimental Learning (M.S. thesis by Olsen), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Rorschach Patterns of Successful College Students (Ph.D. dissertation by Olsen), 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Psychodiagnostics (collection of Rorschach plates), circa 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Development and Standardization of a Projective Occupational Attitudes Test (final report by Olsen, U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Development of a Projective Technique for Obtaining Educationally Useful Information Indicating Pupils' Attitudes Toward Work and Occupational Plans (final report by Olsen and Venema, U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- An Investigation of the Efficacy of Vicarious Group Counseling (final report by Olsen and Melchert, Washington State Department of Public Instruction), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Student Personnel Services: Two and Four Year Colleges (unpublished book-length manuscript by Olsen), circa 1966 (Box 1-2, Folder 6-9)
- Emphasis and Trends in the Areas of Personnel and Guidance (unpublished article by Olsen), circa 1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Other writings, 1971 and undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Diplomas, 1948-1955 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Obituaries and memorial certificate, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)